[Music]
Reedman
reads The Giver by Lois Lowry narrated by phaser Reedman chapter
[Music]
15 Jonas entered the Annex room and realized immediately that it was a day
when he would be sent away.
The Giver was rigid in his chair, his face in his hands. "I'll come back tomorrow, sir," he
said quickly. Then he hesitated. "Unless maybe there's something I can do to
help." The Giver looked up at him, his face contorted with suffering. "Please," he
gasped, "take some of the pain." Jonas helped to his chair at the
side of the bed. Then he quickly removed his tunic and lay face down. "Put your
hands on me," he directed, aware that in such anguish The Giver might need
reminding. The hands came, and the pain came with them and through
them. Jonas braced himself and entered the memory which was torturing The
Giver. He was in a confused, noisy foul smelling place place. It was daylight,
early morning, and the air was thick with smoke that hung, yellow and brown, above the
ground. Around him, everywhere, far across the expanse of what seemed to be a
field like groaning men. A Wildey horse, its brial torn and
dangling, trotted frantically through the mounds of men, tossing its head wiing in
panic. It stumbled, finally, then fell, and did not
rise. Jonas heard a voice next to him.
"Water," the voice said in a parched, croaking whisper. He turned his head toward the
voice and looked into the half closed eyes of a boy who seemed not much older than
himself. Dirt Streed the boy's face and as mad had blonde
hair. He lay sprawled, his gray uniform glistening with wet, fresh
blood. The colors of the carnage were grotesquely bright: the crimson wetness on the rough
and dusty fabric, the ripped shreds of grass, startlingly green, in the boy's yellow
[Music]
hair. The boy stared at him.
"Water," he begged again. When he spoke, a new spurt of blood
drenched the coarse cloth across his chest and
sleeve. One of Jonas's arms was immobilized with pain, and he could see
through his own torn sleev something that looked like ragged flesh and splintery
bone. He tried his remaining arm and felt it move. Slowly he reached to his side, felt
the metal container there, and removed its cap, stopping the small motion of his
hand now and then to wait for the surging pain to
[Music]
ease. Finally, when the container was open, he extended his arm slowly across the
blood soaked earth, inch by inch, and held it to the lips of the
boy. Water trickled into the imploring mouth and down the grimy chin.
The boy sighed. His head fell back, his lower jaw dropping as if he had been surprised by
something. A dull blankness slid slowly across his
[Music]
eyes. He was
silent. But the noise continued all around: the cries of the wounded men, the
cries begging for water and for m Mother and for death. Horses lying on the ground
shrieked, raised their heads, and stabbed randomly toward the sky with their
hooves. From the distance, Jonas could hear the thud of
cannons. Overwhelmed by pain, he lay there in the fearsome stench for
hours listen to the men and animals die, and learn what war warfare
meant. Finally, when he knew that he could bear it no longer and would welcome death
himself, he opened his eyes and was once again on the
[Music]
bed. The Giver looked away, as if he could not bear to see what he had done to
Jonas. "Forgive me," he said
[Music]